# Rômulo Oliveira

Fortaleza, Brazil +55 85 981337203 romulo.oliveira@romin.dev.br <u>Linkedin</u> <u>Github</u> Portfolio

Software developer with +4 years' experience in web development. Skilled in coding, debugging, testing and maintaining applications. Proven ability to create and maintain high-quality software.

#### **Skills**

PHP, Ruby, JavaScript, TypeScript, Laravel, Ruby on Rails, React, Node, Vue, Next, Nuxt, Astro, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Livewire, Bulma, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Docker, PostgreSQL, Git, Gitflow, Github, Aws, CI/CD, Gitlab, Scrum, Kanban.

## **Experience**

2024 - NOW

#### Back-End Developer / Intersol - Fortaleza, Brazil

Back-end development on tax solutions using Ruby on Rails. I develop and maintain integrated systems for various municipalities, optimizing municipal tax management. My work involves implementing new features, fixing bugs, and continuous improvements. Additionally, I collaborate with the team to ensure the efficiency and scalability of the applications.

Main Techs: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, BitBucker.

2022 - 2024

### Software Developer / Hahn Software - Germany

Development and maintenance of a driver's license registration and management system for the German government. I actively contributed to the design, development and ongoing refinement of innovative solutions for the project. My tasks also include code reviews, testing and writing detailed documentation to ensure quality and usability.

#### Activities:

- Development of front-end features.
- Implementing new features
- Bug fixing
- Code reviews
- E2e testing
- Documentation
- CI/CD
- Agile workflow (Scrum, Kanban)

Main Techs: Typescript, Javascript, Vue.js, Bulma, C#, .NET, Docker, Kubernets.

2020 - 2022

#### Full-Stack Developer / Stark Software - Fortaleza, Brazil

- Developed projects using modern web technologies and techniques such as HTML5, CSS3 Javascript, PHP and Ruby.
- Responsible for integration of APIs made in Laravel and Ruby on Rails
- Worked on the development of SASS systems, together with another developer, using Next.js.
- Carrying out code reviews to ensure product quality.
- Application of agile methodology in the projects developed.

Main Techs: Javascript, Typescript, Ruby, PHP, Ruby on Rails, Laravel, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Tailwind, Typescript, Mysql, PostgreSQL, SQlite, Docker, AWS, Git, Gitlab, Github.

## **Education**

2022 - 2024

#### **Systems Analysis and Development** / Uninassau

I learned to develop and implement software solutions to solve complex problems. I explored programming languages, data structures, algorithms and software development methodologies. In addition, I acquired skills in requirements analysis, system design, testing and software maintenance. The course also covered aspects of project management and teamwork, preparing me to work in various areas of information technology.

## **About me**

I am a software developer with over 5 years of experience specializing in web development and back-end solutions.

Currently, as a Back-End Developer at Intersol, I work on optimizing tax solutions for municipalities using Ruby on Rails, ensuring system efficiency and scalability.

Previously, at Hahn Software in Germany, I contributed to the development of a driver's license management system for the German government, handling everything from feature development to code reviews and documentation, while working with a modern tech stack including TypeScript, Vue.js, and Docker.

Additionally, as a Full-Stack Developer at Stark Software, I have developed and integrated various web projects, using PHP, Ruby on Rails, and Next.js. My strong technical background and experience in agile environments allow me to deliver high-quality solutions tailored to each client's needs.

# **Personal Projects**

Some complete projects that I have developed and are in production:

Marvel Snap Brasil: Oficial Brazilian Portal fan-website for the game Marvel Snap.

Link: Visitar

Easy POS: The Easy POS System is a free solution designed for small entrepreneurs,

focused on simplicity and ease of use, even on mobile devices.

Link: Visitar

**Agenda Fácil**: Scheduling system for companies in various industries.

Link: Visitar

Papasand's Restaurant: Multi-user restaurant system with ordering system and

trolley.

Link: Visitar

**Romin Notes**: Multi-user, multi-language system for managing text notes.

Link: Visitar

**Romin Chats**: Real-time chat system with multiple rooms.

Link: Visitar

More projects on my github: Link

## Other skills

- Professional English
- Conversational Spanish
- Easy communication
- Experience with teamwork